For the last five years,
على مدى السنوات الخمس الماضية،
I have documented the lives of teenage mothers in Latin America.
عملت على توثيق حياة الأمهات المراهقات في أمريكا الجنوبية.
I started with a series of photographs
بدأت بسلسلة من الصور الفوتوجرافية
about the moment of birth
عن لحظات الولادة
in my country, Uruguay.
في بلدي، الأوروجواي.
(Video) (Screaming)
(فيديو) (صراخ)
(Grunting)
(جلبة)
(Newborn crying)
(مولود يبكي)
I am the son of a teenage mother
أنا ابن لأم مراهقة
and my sister became a teenage mother when she was 16.
وأختي أصبحت أمًا مراهقة عندما كانت في عمر 16 سنة.
I began exploring the theme
بدأت استكشاف الموضوع
to better understand myself and my origins.
لأفهم أكثر عن نفسي ونشأتي.
In developing countries,
في البلدان النامية،
7.3 million girls under the age of 18
هناك 7.3 مليون فتاة تحت عمر 18 عامًا
give birth each year.
يلدن كل سنة.
Projections suggest
تشير التقديرات
that the teen pregnancy rate in Latin America
أن معدلات حمل المراهقات في أمريكا الجنوبية
will be the highest in the world
ستكون الأعلى في العالم
for the next 80 years.
للثمانين عامًا القادمة.
In Mexico, almost one in two sexually active adolescents
في المكسيك، هناك تقريبًا واحدة من كل اثنتين من المراهقات النشيطات جنسيًا
get pregnant between the ages of 12 to 19 years old.
تحمل في العمر من 12 إلى 19 عامًا.
Teenage pregnancy is not just about young pregnancies.
لا يتعلق الحمل في سن المراهقة بحمل فتيات صغيرات فحسب
It is about gender violence,
إنما أيضًا بالعنف على أساس الجنس،
physical, symbolic, psychological and economic violence.
عنف جسدي، ومعنوي، ونفسي، واقتصادي.
Girls who become pregnant before they are 18
الفتيات اللاتي تحملن قبل سن 18 عامًا
rarely achieve an adequate standard of living.
نادرًا ما يحققن مستوى جيد في المعيشة.
The pattern of poverty
أنماط الفقر،
and limited access to education and health care
والقدر المحدود من التعليم والرعاية الصحية
are a common thread among teen pregnancies.
هي الخيط الرفيع الذي يربط بين المراهقات الحوامل.
If a girl in Latin America gets pregnant before she is 16,
إذا حملت فتاة من أمريكا اللاتينية قبل سن 16 سنة،
the risk of maternal death increases fourfold
فسيزداد خطر موتها بنسبة أربعة أضعاف
over a woman in their 20s.
أكثر من اللائي يحملن في عمرالعشرينيات.
And somehow, in spite of all this,
وعلى نحو ما، على الرغم من كل هذا،
motherhood also imparts a status
فإن الأمومة تضفي على المراهقة مكانةً،
and a respect to the adolescent in her community.
واحترامًا داخل مجتمعها.
Her child becomes her life project.
ويصبح طفلها مشروع حياتها.
A high percentage of girls under the age of 18 are single mothers,
نسبة كبيرة من الأمهات تحت سن 18عازبات،
as was my mother.
مثلما كانت أمي،
When I was learning to be a parent,
عندما كنت أتعلم أن أكون أبًا،
I began to focus on the relationship between father and child,
ركزت على العلاقة بين الأب والطفل،
a subject rarely given much attention.
وهو موضوع نادرًا ما يلقى الاهتمام.
I wanted to highlight the ways
أردت أن أسلط الضوء على الطرق
in which we need to educate boys differently
التي نحتاجها لتعليم الفتيان بشكل مختلف
without turning them into macho men.
بحيث لا يتحولون إلى متباهين بفحولتهم.
In some cases, families send boys to school but not girls.
في بعض الحالات ترسل الأسر الفتيان إلى المدرسة وليس الفتيات.
The persistence of teen pregnancy heightened the gender equity gap
زاد الحمل في سن المراهقة الفجوة بين الجنسين
and the continued existence of traditional roles.
والوجود المستمر للقواعد التقليدية.
If we were to allow equal opportunities to girls,
فلو أتحنا الفرص المتكافئة للفتيات،
they could gain independence.
كن سيحصلن على الإستقلالية.
Educating girls is key
تعليم الفتيات هو السبيل
to breaking cycles of teen pregnancies.
لكسر دائرة الحمل في سن المراهقة.
Girls getting pregnant between the ages of 10 to 14
الفتيات اللائي يحملن في سن من 10 إلى 14
are an extremely vulnerable population,
هن من الشريحة الضعيفة للغاية،
and they can be easy prey for men twice their age.
ويمكن أن يكن فريسة سهلة لرجال في ضعف عمرهن.
There are many cases of violence,
هناك حالات كثيرة من العنف،
incest and sexual abuse
وزنا المحارم والاعتداء الجنسي
perpetrated against this group.
ارتكبت ضد هذه الشريحة.
This is Gloria.
هذه جلوريا،
She became a teen mother at the age of 12,
أصبحت أمًا مراهقة في سن12 سنة
a result of the ongoing abuse by her father,
نتيجة أن والدها كان ينتهكها جنسيا على نحو متواصل،
who was also raping Gloria's two sisters,
والذي كان يغتصب أيضًا شقيقتيها،
ages 8 and 16.
في سن 8 و 16 عامًا.
In this portrait, she has butterflies in her hair,
في هذه الصورة تضع فراشات على شعرها،
symbols of resurrection.
كرمز للقيامة.
For me, it's extremely important to portray this mother with dignity.
بالنسبة لي من المهم للغاية إظهار هذه الأم مع مسألة الشرف.
Pregnancies among girls younger than 15 is a growing trend,
إن حدوث الحمل بين الفتايات الأصغر من 15 سنة في ازدياد.
not only in Latin America,
ليس في أمريكا اللاتينية فحسب،
but many developing countries in the world.
وإنما في كثير من الدول النامية بالعالم.
Our region is marred by bad social and cultural inequalities,
يشوب منطقتنا عدم المساواة الاجتماعية والثقافية
and teen pregnancy further increases this divide.
ويزيد حمل المراهقات من هذا الانقسام.
I am committing to being part of the solution
أنا ملتزم أن أكون جزءًا من الحل
by making work that implicitly and emphatically
من خلال العمل الدؤوب والمستمر
calls for human rights for girls.
في الدعوة إلى الحقوق الإنسانية للفتيات.
The day life projects for boys and girls become similar,
إذا أصبحت مشاريع الحياة اليومية للفتيان والفتيات متشابهة،
teenage pregnancy will decrease.
سيقل معدل حمل المراهقات.
Thank you.
شكرًا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)